What a beautiful night road, whatever you
Qué bonito via de noche yo lo que tú me
tell me Hey, what did you want to comment on, wait?
digas Oye qué querías comentar espérate
Ah well Ah Ah well You're going to freak out,
Ah bueno Ah Ah bueno Vais a flipar que
no Javi, no, no, I didn't tell you
no Javi que no te lo no se lo he contado
in the chat this morning, well, this morning
al chat esta mañana pues que esta mañana
I saw, well, it's just that I'm getting this thing, I
he visto bueno es que me me da esta cosa
was walking and such, and I had arranged to meet up
estaba andando y tal y y había quedado
with a friend that I made at the
con una amiga que he hecho en el
airport yesterday who was also traveling,
aeropuerto ayer que también viajaba
traveling, have you made any friends? Have you made any
viajaba has hecho amiguitos he hecho
friends? Yes, eh, she's also studying
amiguitos sí eh Además está estudiando
journalism and such. And well, if you see us
periodist y tal Y bueno si nos ves
talking, I say, my
hablando Digo hija mía
goodness, very nice from Pamplona, ​​and Talking Talking
suerte muy maja de Pamplona y Hablando
Talking such. Well, I had arranged to meet
Hablando Hablando tal Pues justo había
up with her this morning at the
quedado con ella esta mañana en la
cathedral and we did
cathedral para la catedral y hemos hecho
like a tour and just as we were walking, I think
como un tour y justo andando creo que
we saw a
hemos visto un
suicide, you can't say that
suicidio no se puede decir esa
word, no. I mean, we saw
palabra no O sea hemos visto suici
suicide, taking a life, taking a life, we've seen a taking a life, taking a life, you saw, you saw, literally, but the police came, here they're called the police, and they were investigating and such. And of course, of course, here they speak in German and we
claro claro aquí hablan en alemán y no
weren't understanding anything, but we were
estbamos entendiendo nada pero nos hemos
amazed and you know what?  I'm what I'm what
alucinadas y sabes lo que me lo que me a
I remembered J daughter what no It's not that I've been stiff I
lo que me acordado J hija el qué no No
say go well I
es que me he quedado tiesa digo ve pues
was
me estaba
remembering because I remember well at that
acordando porque me acuerdo bueno en esa
time Not because I was little or I
época No porque yo era era chiquita o
was a teenager but I remember that I
era adolescente pero me acuerdo que
dealt with this subject a lot and it made me very
traté mucho es tema y me dio muchísima
sad that it was
pena que fue
when Erik Ortiz the sister of
cuando cuando Erik Ortiz la hermana de
Queen Letizia got out of the way
de la reina Leticia se se quitó se quitó
eh look doing a reflection walking
eh fíjate haciendo una reflexión andando
that I was commenting on it to this girl
que se lo estaba comentando a esta chica
eh look Erica Ortiz who was 31
eh fíjate Erica Ortiz que tenía 31
years old lived who is the mother of Carla Vigo
años vivía que es la madre de Carla vigo
and lived in Valde Bernardo in Madrid in
e vivía en valde Bernardo en Madrid en
the apartment that was previously
el piso de que anteriormente era el piso
Queen Letizia's single apartment
de soltera de la reina Leticia
eh she lived there eh it was known it was known by
eh vivía allí eh se sabía se conocía por
everyone that she had mental health problems eh
todos que tenía problemas eh de Salud
But well when it seemed that
Mental Pero bueno cuando parecía que las
things were going
cosas que las cosas iban
better she decided to get out of the way I will never
mejor decidió quitarse de medio nunca se
forget C Los
me olvidará C heladera de Los
Almendros refrigerator seventh floor of a block of
Almendros séptimo piso de un bloque de
11 is that I say it because I mean I don't know
11 es que yo lo digo porque o sea no sé
why I'm sharing this now
por qué Estoy compartiendo esto ahora
but I'm remembering because I
pero me estoy acordando porque ahí
was there  I was there a couple of years ago, well, let's see
estuve yo hace un par de años pues a ver
what it was, damn, how fast Javi,
qué había sido Qué rápido Javi
uh, I was there a couple of years ago
eh ahí estuve yo hace un par de años
because that apartment, uh, that belonged to Queen
porque ese piso eh que era de la reina
Letizia and then it happened, she left it to
Leticia y luego pasó se lo se lo dejó a
her sister,
su hermana
uh, it was an apartment that at the time
eh era un piso que en su momento lo
they called it, [ __ ], they all called it the
llamaban lo llamaban allí todos el
cursed apartment because before that happened
piso maldito porque antes de que pasara
with Queen Letizia's sister there had
eso con la hermana de la reina Leticia
also been other uh incidents
también había habido otros eh incidentes
what's going on what the end yes yes no no no no no the
qué es lo que pasa que final sí sí no no
same but incidents what's
no no no iguales pero incidentes qué es
going on it's p yes it was sold for I
lo que pasa que es p se sí se vendió por
think it was
creo que fueron
230,000 about 15 16 years ago and when I
230,000 hace unos 15 16 años y cuando yo
went uh the neighbors told us Well, I
fui eh nos contaban los vecinos Bueno
went with a friend
fui con un compañero
and the neighbors told us anecdotes about
e nos contaban los vecinos anécdotas de
when they were when the
cuando que eran cuando se conocieron la
queen and and and King Felipe met, that he went on a
reina y y y el rey Felipe que él iba en
motorcycle, a motilla, well, a Vespa,
moto en una una motilla pues una Vespa
uh, he went with his helmet, he didn't fit through the
eh iba con su casco no entraba por el
garage uh in a super discreet way, he
garaje eh de una manera super discreta
went up in the elevator with his helmet in the
subía en ascensor con el casco en el
elevator uh those were like his first
ascensor eh ahí eran como sus primeras
get-togethers with friends was when they
quedadas con amigos era cuando se
met and everything and that apartment has like
conocieron y todo y ese piso tiene como
Well of course it's not going to have history it has
Bueno claro no va a tener historia tiene
history and and it was sold and
historia y y se vendió y lo tuvieron
obviously the owners who
evidentemente los dueños que lo
bought it uh were knowledgeable about they knew
compraron eh eran conocedores de sabían
the apartment they were buying and they
el piso que estaban comprando y lo
wanted to renovate it completely as a result of that they
quisieron reformar entero a raíz de eso
completely turned it upside down
entero le dieron la la vuelta entera
so that it didn't seem like it didn't
para que no como como por cosa de que no
have anything that the
tuviera nada de lo que tenía el piso
previous apartment had and and they're still there I came back two
anterior y y siguen ahí volví hace dos
years ago and they're still there the same
años y siguen ahí los mismos
owners the owners have never
propietarios los propietarios nunca han
wanted obviously it's normal and totally
querido obvio es normal y totalmente
legitimate they have never wanted to talk about what
lícito nunca han querido hablar de lo
uh well about the Hey well like typical
que Eh pues del Oye pues cómo típicas
curiosities that maybe people here don't
curiosidades que igual la gente aquí no
understand about Hey what is the apartment like uh
entiende de Oye cómo es el piso eh
when they bought it because they
cuando lo compraron porque se lo
bought it from her or rather how was the
compraron a ella o sea cómo fue la
purchase the typical curious details
compra los típicos detalles de curiosos
that people might be interested in no and
que a la gente le puede interesar no y
in the end Well look from there she left a
al final Pues mira de ahí dejó a una
girl like Carla an orphan very very
niña como es Carla huérfana muy muy
young Carla has also had several
jovencita Carla también ha tenido varios
problems uh mental health I don't know that
problemas eh de Salud Mental no sé esa
girl I admire how she has gotten ahead
niña Yo admiro Cómo ha salido adelante a
despite her things there are many people who  It's
pesar de sus cosas hay mucha gente que
a shame that she's been laughed at
me da mucha pena que se ha reído de ella
many times. I've seen her a couple of
muchas veces Yo la he visto un par de
times and I think she's a lovely girl and I
veces y me parece una niña encantadora y
know that there are people who have
sé que hay personas que se han
taken advantage of her and it makes me very sad and
aprovechado de ella y me da mucha pena y
I hope that all goes very well for her, as
yo espero que le vaya muy bien todo lo
best I can and I remember that at
mejor que pueda y me acuerdo que cuando
that funeral, Queen Letizia
ese funeral la reina Leticia intentó
tried to cover it up so that the press wouldn't
intentó tapar para que la prensa no se
find out and it wouldn't have any
enterase y no tuviera ninguna
significance because they didn't understand how,
trascendencia porque no entendían como
uh, the press wanted to go to the funeral,
eh la prensa pues quería ir al funeral
wanted to uh know more details about what happened.
quería eh saber más datos de lo sucedido
In the end, Letizia was
al final ella Leticia estaba embarazada
6 months pregnant with Infanta Sofia, I
de 6 meses de la infanta Sofía me
remember perfectly and they didn't understand
acuerdo perfectamente y y no entendían
the interest of the press, obviously she
el interés de la prensa evidentemente lo
had it and in the end, sadly, well, the
tenía y al final tristemente Pues el
morbid always wins but it's very heavy, 31
morvo siempre gana pero es muy heavy 31
years old, 31 years old, she had taken
años 31 años tenía una ingesta de
tranquilizers and she got away, she got out of the way
tranquilizantes y y se quitó se quitó en
and I remember that after that, Javi,
medio y me acuerdo que a raí de ahí Javi
the issue of Mental Health was put on
el tema de la Salud Mental se puso sobre
the table both in public institutions
la mesa tanto en instituciones públicas
and in well, yes, politicians, people of
como Bueno sí políticos gente de la
culture. And imagine what it's worth, they give
cultura Y fíjate tú de lo que sirve dan
a few words, they say four things and to
unas palabras dicen cuatro cosas y a día
this day, 18 years  des Well almost what a shame eh it
de hoy 18 años des Pues casi qué pena eh
seems yes
parece sí
totally that something has been heard again
totalmente que se volvió a saber algo
about Peñafiel, girl, what a barbarity that gave
del peñafiel tía vaya barbaridad que dio
eh Ah yes, I wrote to him, I didn't tell you, I
eh Ah sí le escribí no te cont yo
also
también le
wrote to him but that man doesn't answer
escribí pero ese hombre no contesta él
WhatsApp No well yes to me uh I
al WhatsApp No pues sí a mí me eh yo le
told him like Of course because I don't know at
dije en plan Claro porque yo no sé en
what point because supposedly he was going to
qué punto porque supuestamente iba a
appear in something related to
salir en algo relacionado con con
Bárbara Rey, something that they were going to broadcast that
Bárbara Rey algo que iban a emitir que
he was going to appear or I don't know what, look it up on the
iba a salir él o no sé qué míralo en
internet, something, something related to
internet algo algo relacionado con
Bárbara Rey, I don't know exactly,
Bárbara Rey No sé exactamente el que
then I asked him and he says I'm not going to
entonces le pregunté y me dice no voy a
do anything, I'm not going to say anything, like they've
hacer nada no voy a decir nada como que
recommended that he stay out of the
le han recomendado estar fuera del foco
media spotlight because let's remember the last thing he
mediático porque recordemos lo último
did, what a barbarity I mean, that they
que hizo qué barbaridad quiero decir que
fired him from Hoya eh for those who don't
le despedir de Hoya eh para el que no se
remember, for those who don't remember, he went to
acuerde para el que no recuerde se fue a
a YouTube program which by the way
un programa de YouTube que por cierto
that program is eh a YouTube podcast
ese programa es eh un podcast de Youtube
by Gaona, it's called no that he's a doctor, no, I do
de Gaona se llama no que es un doctor no
n't know if he's a doctor or a scientist, I don't
no sé si es un doctor o un científico No
know exactly who he is, I know that he
sé exactamente quién es s sé que va
sometimes goes to Iker's program but
algunas veces al programa de Iker pero
this man when Jaime  peñafiel said
este hombre cuando Jaime peñafiel dijo
That nonsense on his YouTube channel
Esa barbaridad en su canal de YouTube
that what he said was that the reason
que lo que dijo fue que la la razón por
Erica took her life was because
la que Erica se quitó la vida fue porque
she had lent him let's say the
ella le había prestado digamos el
pregnancy So
embarazo O sea que que
Leticia couldn't get pregnant because of
Leticia no podía quedarse embarazada por
the abortions she had had no and that and that
los abortos que había tenido no y que y
the oculi were from the sister no I
que los óculos eran de de la hermana no
mean like the like that the
O sea como que los como que que la
sister had the girls the two girls
hermana tuvo a las niñas a las dos niñas
that hadn't even been born or rather
que no había nacido ni siquiera o sea
the oldest had been born the youngest no
había nacido la mayor la pequeña no
Leticia was pregnant with the
Leticia estaba embarazada de la de la
second but well that
segunda pero que bueno que la que
Leticia wouldn't let her see the girls
Leticia no le dejaba ver a las niñas
something like that that's why she took her life it's
algo así que por eso se quitó la vida es
like host But the thing is that I will never
como Pero es que yo nunca
fully understand it they have explained it to me you
entenderé del todo me la han explicado
have tried to explain it to me a thousand
me la habéis intentado explicar mil
times but I will not understand why the
veces pero no entenderé porque la casa
royal house does not sue you I have told you or
real no demanda Te lo te lo he dicho o
rather Look if you go into any
sea Mira si tú entras en cualquier medio
digital media or people I don't
de comunicación digital o gente no
repeat like Pilar eire eh people
repito como Pilar eire eh gente
like but a lot of people who are very
como pero cantidad de gente que son muy
good novelists write very well speak
buenas novelistas escribe muy bien habla
very well novels very well I never think that
muy bien novela muy bien nunca creo que
once the house of  Pilar
una vez le desmintió la casa de la Pilar
once when they already exceed x limit or
una vez cuando ya sobrepasan x límite o
x thing that doesn't interest them How are they going to get
x cosa que no les interesan Cómo se van
involved in all these things because
a meter en todas estas cosas porque
the institution would lose credibility if it got
perdería credibilidad la institución de
involved in things like RTVE can get involved,
entrar a cosas como puede entrar rtve
for example, they say that such a
que ve por ejemplo que dicen tal
program is canceled tomorrow, well no, RTV
programa se cancela mañana pues no rtv
doesn't deny this information, such a
no eh desmiente esta información tal
program. Well, the Royal House as an
programa Bueno pero la casa Real Como
institution is going to get involved in denying whether
institución se va a meter a desmentir si
Juan Carlos has called his son for such a thing,
Juan Carlos ha llamado su hijo para tal
no. I mean, you continuously see the
no O sea tú ves continuamente los medios
media every day,
de comunicación todos los días la
Infanta Elena, for example, today rebounded,
infanta Elena por ejemplo hoy rebotada
well, the maximum Cabrio of Infanta
bueno el máximo Cabrio de la infanta
Elena with her daughter called her yesterday, such a thing, but
Elena con su hija la llamó ayer tal pero
you believe that it is going to enter the
tú te crees que va a entrar a la
institution, did Infanta Elena call
institución no llamó la infanta Elena a
Victoria Federica when they are already part of the
Victoria Federica cuando ya son de la
royal family, but they are not, you know. I mean, I don't
familia real pero no son sabes O sea no
want to tell you, it doesn't make sense, they are
te quiero decir no tiene sentido no lo
never, ever going to do it. So
van a hacer nunca nunca Entonces se toma
people take the liberty, both on
la libertad a la gente tanto en
television, on the radio, and in the
televisión como en radio como en prensa
written press, to say whatever they want
escrita de decir lo que les dé la gana
without any consequences, and they will never
sin ninguna consecuencia y no la va a
have any. And you can read
tener nunca Y tú puedes leer titulares
brutal headlines and people click because it generates
brutales y la gente clica porque da
a lot of traffic, the royal house is what  It
muchísimo tráfico la casa real es lo que
works better on the internet to read I don't
mejor funciona en internet para leer No
know if on YouTube but on the internet the
sé si en YouTube pero en internet el
traffic of the royal house is
tráfico de la casa real es bárbaro o sea
barbaric, I mean it's an outrage I don't know if it's
es una barbaridad no sé si ahora está
calmer now I think that now there was a
más calmada creo que ahora está hubo una
very strong time now I think it's calmed down
época muy fuerte ahora creo que se calmó
a bit in fact Jaime
un poco de hecho los propios t de Jaime
del Burgo's own t's don't pull anymore either No
del burgo ya no ya no tiran tampoco Por
matter how much he tries to get attention from
más que intenta llamar la atención de
time to time but but yes yes I mean it's
vez en cuando pero pero sí sí o sea es
very strong let's see It's that you know what happens is that
muy fuerte a ver Es que sabes qué pasa
this is the judicial issue people
que esto es el el tema judicial la gente
mix up complaints with
mezcla las denuncias con las demandas
civil lawsuits and people believe that a
civiles y la gente se cree que una
lawsuit is something like in court they
demanda es algo como es en el juzgado
believe that it's the same as a
pues se cree que es lo mismo que una
complaint and of course people have to
denuncia y claro la gente lo que tiene
understand that a lawsuit, which is what is
que entender que una demanda que es lo
requested for the right to honor, is
que se pide por el derecho al honor es
a civil thing, it's basically claiming
una cosa civil es básicamente reclamar
money so clo you imagine a
dinero entonces clo tú imagínate una
queen or the King filing a lawsuit against you in
reina o el Rey poniéndote una demanda en
England, yes they do it Eh in England they are
Inglaterra sí lo hacen Eh en Inglaterra
terrified of And a lot of respect for the
le tienen terror a Y mucho respeto a la
royal house because they do sue eh the
casa real porque sí demandan eh a los
media and whoever is necessary but here not Of
medios y a quien haga falta pero aquí no
course because it seems like of course you are
Claro porque se ve como claro le estás
making a lawsuit you are  asking for
haciendo una demanda le estás pidiendo
money but there is a crime which
dinero pero sí que existe un delito que
is insulting the crown and I
son las injurias a la corona y yo
consider that there are times that eh here I
Considero que hay veces que eh aquí
continue every day but look at the
continu todos los días pero fíjate tú el
respect that has been lost for King Juan
respeto que se le ha perdido al rey Juan
Carlos, already the emeritus, none Look how they
Carlos ya el emérito ninguno Mira cómo
talk about it now, I mean respect in the
se habla ya de o sea respeto en el
sense of Before there was certain when he had
sentido de Antes había cierto cuando
power there was a certain respect bar
tenía poder había cierto respeto barra
fear on television to broadcast according to What
miedo en televisión a emitir según Qué
things now they publish his photos with
cosas ahora se publica sus fotos con
Barbara Rey he doesn't have any kind of but let's
Bárbara Rey no tiene ningún tipo de pero
see, it's that you confuse that it's not that
a ver es que confundes que no es que se
respect has been lost or that he has been allowed Let's
le haya perdido el respeto ni que se le
see, it's that
haya per A ver es que se está hablando
things are being talked about now that were previously censored
ahora cosas que antes estaban censuradas
from talking about but respect has not been
de hablar pero el respeto no se le ha
lost for him nobody is disrespecting him
perdido nadie le está faltando de
What is being said is the
respeto Lo que se está diciendo es la
truth that he had girlfriends everywhere
verdad que tenía novias por todas partes
that he cheated on Sofia for me
que le ponía los cuernos a Sofía para mí
that is for for me that is clear
eso es para para para mí eso es claro
for me that is losing respect on a
para mí eso es perderle el respeto a
public level not disrespecting him with
nivel público no faltarle al respeto de
insults but losing Of course, of course, of course
insulto sino perder Claro claro claro el
respect in terms of losing respect
respeto en cuanto a perderle respeto
for me, for example, Well, of course,
para mí ejemp Bueno claro faltarle
disrespecting him is what they do with Leticia, of
respeto es lo que hacen con Leticia
course  That's no and for example I'll give you
claro eso es No y por ejemplo te pongo
an example Isabel Pantoja when she had
un ejemplo Isabel Pantoja cuando tenía
a contact with tele5 and she was in Idol
un contato con tele5 y estaba en Idol
Kids or I don't know what it was Maravillosa as
Kids o no sé qué era Maravillosa en
soon as no you don't want to be with telec BM
cuanto no no quieres estar con telec BM
Bom BM BM I get out of you what you know what I
Bom BM BM saco de ti lo que sabes lo que
want to tell you is that of course with me
te quiero decir es que claro conmigo
against me eh I don't know eh but come on eh
contra mí eh No sé eh pero vamos eh Es
The subject is heavy and it's what you say that
heavy el tema y es lo que tú dices que
in England it doesn't happen I'll tell you
la en Inglaterra no pasa ya te digo yo
that it doesn't happen come on
que no pasa vamos